(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T08:48:13.870541",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
What can I do for you?
I can hear you.
あの日ココロの彼方に
Far beyond the hazy borders of my heart,
描いてた場所にいる
I can see a place... It's something like this.
途方に暮れてたりする
Every now and then, I don't know what to do.
けだでもう戻れない
Still, I know that I... can never go back.
夢に見たカタチとはなにもかもが違う
All the things I've seen in those hazy dreams
現実には眩暈さえする
Can't compare to what I see tonight.
眩暈さえする
Everything's so different that it brings me to my knees...
リアルな世界に揺れてる感情負けたくない
And though I know the world of real emotion has surrounded me, I won't give into it.
もうただ走るしかないこの胸に
Now, I know, that forward is the only way my heart can go.
聴こえてくる
I hear your voice calling out to me,
キミは一人じゃない
"You'll never be alone."
What can I do for you?
あの日ココロの彼方に 描いていた場所にいる
I pictured myself somewhere far in my heart that day
途方に暮れてたりする だけどもう戻れない
It becomes dark in the distance, but I can no longer return
夢に見たカタチとは なにもかもが違う
The shape I saw in my dream is different from everything
現実には… 眩暈さえする
I become dizzy from reality...
リアルな世界に揺れてる感情
The feeling of swaying in the real world
負けたくない
I don't want to lose
もうただ走るしかないこの胸に
The only thing I can hear from my heart is to run.
聴こえてくる キミは一人じゃない
You are not alone
決して振り向きはしない あなたには頼らない
I won't turn back, I won't rely on you
なにかがあれば 必ず すぐに来てくれるから
Because if something happens, you'll always come to me quickly
いまぼくにできること それは信じること…
The only thing I can do now is to believe...
真実なら この胸にある
The truth is in my heart
だから、一人じゃない
So, I am not alone
What can I do for you?
I can hear you
リアルな世界に揺れてる感情 感じても
The feeling of swaying in the real world, even if you feel it
あなたが目を閉じたならそこにいる
If you close your eyes, I will be there
絆がある だから、一人じゃない
There is a bond, so you are not alone
リアルな世界に揺れてる感情 負けたくない
The feeling of swaying in the real world, I don't want to lose
もうただ走るしかないこの胸に 聴こえてくる
The only thing I can hear from my heart is to run
キミは一人じゃない リアルな世界に揺れてる感情
You are not alone. The feeling of swaying in the real world
負けたくない もうただ
I don't want to lose, just
走るしかないこの胸に 聴こえてくる
to run with this feeling in my heart
キミは 一人じゃない
You are not alone
What can I do for you?
I can hear you
踊ってるだけで退場 それをそっかそっかと言って
I walk out of a dance saying "that's it, that's it"
お幸せについて議論 何が正義なんかって思う
Discussing happiness and thinking what justice is
生意気そうにガム噛んで それもいいなって思う
Chewing gum cheekily, I think that's good too
テレスコープ越しの感情 ロックに全部詰め込んだ
The telescope is seeing all the emotions I have kept all this time
踊ってない夜を知らない
Without dancing, I don't know a night
踊ってない夜が気に入らない
Without dancing, I don't like a night
踊ってない夜を知らない
Without dancing, I don't know a night
踊ってない夜が気に入らないよ
Without dancing, I don't like a night
気に入らない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I don't care about the night that I don't like
踊ってない夜がない夜なんて とってもとっても退屈です
The night will be very, very boring if there is no dancing
踊ってない夜を知らない
Without dancing, I don't know a night
踊ってない夜が気に入らない
Without dancing, I don't like a night
踊ってない夜を知らない
Without dancing, I don't know a night
踊ってない夜が気に入らないよ
Without dancing, I don't like a night
気に入らない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I don't care about the night that I don't like
踊ってない夜がない夜なんて ととってもとっても退屈です
The night will be very, very boring if there is no dancing
思ってるだけで行動
I act by just thinking
きっとnight音楽も踊る
If you do it, music might dance in the night
ダンスでダンスする現状
I'm dancing in the closet now
これはチャンスなんかって思う
I think this is a chance
カスタネットがほらたんたん たたたたんたたたん
The castanet goes tan tan tata tatan
踊ってない夜を知らない人とか この世に一人もございません
There is no one who knows the night without dancing
踊ってない夜を知らない
Without dancing, I don't know a night
踊ってない夜が気に入らない
Without dancing, I don't like a night
踊ってない夜を知らない
Without dancing, I don't know a night
踊ってない夜が気に入らないよ
Without dancing, I don't like a night
気に入らない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I don't care about the night that I don't like
踊ってない夜がない夜なんて とってもとっても退屈です
The night will be very, very boring if there is no dancing
踊ってるだけ退場
Just dancing, then leaving...
ダンスホールの未来に
In the future of the dance hall...
色を塗っていくのはあなた あなた
You are the one coloring it, you, you!
ダンスは笑顔で待ってる
The dance is waiting with a smile.
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing,
踊ってない夜が気にならない
I don't care about a night without dancing.
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing,
踊ってない夜が気にならないよ
I don't care about a night without dancing.
気に入らない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I no longer know a night I don't like,
踊ってない夜がない夜なんて
A night without a night of dancing...
踊ってたい夜を知りたい
I want to know a night I want to dance,
踊ってたい夜を切り取りたい
I want to capture a night I want to dance.
踊ってたい夜を知りたい
I want to know a night I want to dance,
踊ってない夜が気にならないよ
I don't care about a night without dancing.
気に入らない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I no longer know a night I don't like.
踊ってたい夜がない夜なんて
A night without a night I want to dance...
踊っては踊ってはたいせつで
Dancing, dancing, it's so precious,
踊ってたい夜がたいせつなんです
A night I want to dance is so precious.
とってもとってもとっても大切です
Very, very, very precious!
IRyS, it's IRyS from Hololive English Promise
ホロライブEnglishのIRySです。
I'm IRyS from Hololive English -Promise-.
Welcome to my birthday live, Hope Upon a Star!
Thank you so, so much for coming.
今年もね、誕生日ライブに見にきてくれて、来てくれて、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live!
ホポパナス…あ、今年ね、ちょっと誕生日がよりも、ちょっとだけ…ね、あの、遅いんですけど、誕生日ライブです。
It's a bit later than usual this year, but it's a birthday live.
Yes, it's a little bit later than my actual birthday, but you know, it's no problem.
Please do post your comments and screenshots using the hashtag #IRySBday2025 written over here.
Please post comments and screenshots using the hashtag #IRySBday2025.
I'd be really happy if you took a lot of screenshots cuz there's going to be a lot of cool moments, yay!
I'd be happy if you took lots of screenshots of the cool moments, yay!
でね、今回のライブのハッシュタグはIRySBday2025ね、this?
And for this live stream's hashtag, it's #IRySBday2025, right?
えと、もう、ぜひ感想とかスクショもたくさん撮ってポストしてくれたら嬉しいです！
Please post your impressions and screenshots, I'd be so happy!
えー、じゃあね、えっとちょっと、みんなに見せたいものがあるんだ。I have something I really want to share with you guys, so let me go prepare real quick.
I have something to share with you, so let me go prepare real quick.
じゃん！ It's the sixth best outfit!
Ta-da! It's the 6th Fes outfit!
The color is hope! It's so cute, right?
I love this outfit so much! あのね、今年の6th Fesの衣装、さっそく着てます！ めっちゃくちゃかわいいっしょ？
I love this outfit! I'm already wearing this year's 6th Fes outfit!
もう、最高最高、もう I love this outfit so much, it's just so pretty, it's so elegant, it's so pretty and...
It's the best, so pretty, so elegant, and...
It looks, it looks... yeah. Ah, but what do you guys think? Do you guys think it's cute?
It looks... yeah. But what do you guys think? Do you think it's cute?
Yeah? Very cute! Anyways, the concept of this live concert...
is to sing my favorite songs from different eras of music, focusing on dance and some euro, cuz I know you guys love euro as much as I do, right? Yeah!
...is to sing my favorite songs from different eras, focusing on dance and Eurobeat!
There are also different kinds of music players for each song all over the stage. Can you spot them all?
There are also music players for each song all over the stage. Can you spot them?
今回のライブはね、IRySの好きなダンス曲やユーロビートの曲を懐かしい曲から新しい曲まで、いろんな楽曲デバイスと一緒に歌い倒します！みんな楽しんでってね！
I'll be singing my favorite dance and Eurobeat songs from old to new! Hope you enjoy!
Speaking of which, you know, talking about music devices, what do you guys think of my jukebox?
Speaking of music devices, what do you think of my jukebox?
Isn't it big and cool? Yeah! I put a lot of songs in here.
So how about we start the next song? Yeah! このジュークボックスかっこよくない？もうたくさんの曲が入ってるんだ。
So how about we start the next song? This jukebox has so many songs!
じゃあ早速次の曲いってみようかな？
Shall we go right into the next song?
この後もね、ゲスト曲はたくさんあり、
And after this, there'll be lots of guest songs,
なんと最後の方に、ゲスト大発表もありますんで、
and what's more, towards the very end, there'll be a big guest announcement,
最後まで一緒に楽しんで盛り上げていきましょう！
so let's enjoy it together and get hyped right to the end!
Stay tuned, as we have a lot of guest songs coming up, and I have a big, big, big announcement to share with you all as well!
So exciting, so make sure you watch until the end.
Please listen to Rockin' Hardcore!
Go man go, rockin' over the groove
Everybody go, everybody rise
Spark 'n' glow, baby, squeeze out your soul
Till you're reachin' high, devil in the sky
Fun, fun, baby
Feel all the power, feel all the fire
Move it crazy, shake it to the beat of the night
Rockin' hardcore over the world, stomp your feet back to the ground
Rockin' hardcore, loosin' control
Oh baby, roll just for you
Rockin' hardcore, let yourself go
Move it honey, one more time
Rockin' hardcore, loosin' control
I'm feelin' hot, feelin' good
Run girl run, never chasin' you down
Baby that's no hide, freedom is inside
Devil's son, yes I know I'm the one
Never actin' wise, got no reason why
Fun, fun, baby
Feel all the power, feel all the fire
Move it crazy, shake it to the beat of the night
Rockin' hardcore over the world, stomp your feet back to the ground
Rockin' hardcore, loosin' control
Oh baby, roll just for you
Rockin' hardcore, let yourself go
Move it honey, one more time
Rockin' hardcore, loosin' control
I'm feeling hot, feeling good
Go man go, rockin' over the groove
Spark 'n' glow, baby, squeeze out your soul
Devil in the sky
Fun, fun, baby
Feel all the power, feel all the fire
Move it crazy, shake it to the beat of the night
Rockin' hardcore over the world, stomp your feet back to the ground
Rockin' hardcore, loosin' control
Oh baby, roll just for you
Rockin' hardcore, let yourself go
Move it honey, one more time
Rockin' hardcore, loosin' control
I'm feelin' hot, feelin' good
響き合う 願いが今、覚醒めてく
The resounding wish awakens now,
譲れない未来のために
for the sake of the future I can't surrender.
巡り逢う 運命を超えたその先に
Once I've crossed over the fate I'll meet,
この想い 輝くから
these feelings will shine.
ここじゃない未来に 想い託してみれば
Placing my faith in a future that's not here...
響き合う 願が今、覚醒めてく
The echoing wish awakens now,
譲れない未来のために
for the sake of an unyielding future.
巡り逢える 運命を超えたその先に
Beyond the fate we meet,
この想い輝くから
these feelings will shine.
ここじゃない未来に想い託してみては
Entrusting dreams to a future not here,
強さの本当の意味を探し続けてた
I kept searching for the true meaning of strength.
ありのままの痛みを 受け入れるその意味を
I learned the meaning of accepting pain as it is
明日へ走り続ける君に知った
from you, who keep running toward tomorrow.
巡りゆく 景色が今、流れてく
The revolving scenery flows by now,
手繰り寄せた 世界の先
beyond the world I pulled close.
降り注ぐ シグナルを 身体で感じて
Feel the signals raining down upon your body,
解き放つ 今全てを
and release everything now!
Just truth in my heart いつだって迷わないよ
Just truth in my heart, I'll never be lost,
消せない想いがあるから
because I have feelings that cannot be erased.
解き明かす 真実から 瞳を逸らさずに
Without turning my eyes away from the truth,
I'll reach the next stage to realize all.
遠く 感じてた 君が走る背中を
From far away, I sensed your back as you ran.
いつからだろう こんなにも近くに感じる
I wonder since when I've felt you this close.
不安隠し切れずに
Unable to hide my anxiety,
迫る空を見上げた
I looked up at the approaching sky.
傷ついた記憶 いつか乗り越えるよ
I will overcome my wounded memories someday.
憧れは 能力を今 呼び起こす
Aspiration awakens my power right now,
守りたいものがあるから
because there is something I want to protect.
巡りゆく 景色胸に 駆け上がるだけ
The revolving scenery surges in my chest, I'll just run up.
痛みは風に消えてく
My pain fades away into the wind.
Believe in Judgelight 運命さえ 打ち抜いて
Believe in Judgelight, shooting through even destiny!
夜明けをこの手で造ろう
Let's create the dawn with these hands.
変えていく 勇気と変わらない心で
With the courage to change and an unchanging heart,
I believe myself and precious emotion
打ち砕く この想いで
I will smash through with these feelings!
始まりの 光の中、誓い合う
In the light of the beginning, we make our pledge,
果てなき闇を裁くこと
to judge the endless darkness.
恐れてた 孤独の渦 溺れることに
I was afraid of drowning in the vortex of loneliness,
だけどもう振り返らない
but I won't look back anymore.
巡りゆく 景色が今、流れてく
The revolving scenery flows by now,
手繰り寄せた 世界の先
beyond the world I pulled close.
降り注ぐ シグナルを 身体で感じて
Feel the signals raining down upon your body,
解き放つ 今全てを
and release everything now!
Just truth in my heart いつだって迷わないよ
Just truth in my heart, I'll never be lost,
消せない想いがあるから
because I have feelings that cannot be erased.
解き明かす 真実から 瞳を逸らさずに
Without turning my eyes away from the truth,
I'll reach the next stage to realize all.
確かな 絆 信じて
Believing in our unwavering bond.
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One Room Disco
ディスコ ディスコ ワンルーム・ディスコ
Disco, disco, one room disco!
ディスコ ディスコ
Disco, disco!
ディスコ ディスコ ワンルーム・ディスコ
Disco, disco, one room disco!
なんだって つくなめ 半分の生活
Living a half-life where anything can happen,
だけど荷物は重い 気分は軽い
yet my luggage is heavy and my mood is light.
窓をあけても 見慣れない風景
Even when I open the window, the scenery is unfamiliar.
ちょっと落ち着かないけれど そのうち楽しくなるでしょ
I feel a little uneasy, but I'm sure it'll get fun soon.
新しい場所でうまくやっていけるかな
Wondering if I can get along well in a new place,
部屋を片付けて 買い物に出かけよ
I clean up my room and head out for shopping.
遠い空の向こう キミは何を思うの?
What are you thinking beyond the distant sky?
たぶんできるはずって思わなくちゃしょうがない
I just have to believe I can do it.
ディスコ ディスコ ワンルーム・ディスコ
Disco, disco, one room disco!
ディスコ ディスコ
Disco, disco!
買い物に出かけよ
Let's go out shopping.
遠い空の向こう
Beyond the distant sky,
キミは何を思うの
what are you thinking about?
たぶんできるはずって
Thinking that surely we can do it,
思わなきゃしょうがない
we have no choice but to believe.
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One room disco
ディスコ ディスコ
Disco, disco
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One room disco
ディスコ ディスコ
Disco, disco
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One room disco
ディスコ ディスコ
Disco, disco
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One room disco
ディスコ ディスコ
Disco, disco
なんたってすぐなめ
I've got a little less of everything,
半分の生活
living half a life.
だけど気になるカロリー
But I'm minding my calories,
気分は軽い
and my mood is light.
シャンプーをしながら
While shampooing
目を閉じたまま
with my eyes closed,
シャワーも出せないけれど
I can't even run the shower yet,
そのうち慣れてくるでしょ
but I'm sure I'll get used to it soon.
新しい場所で
In this new place,
上手やっていけるかな
I wonder if I'll get by just fine.
音楽をかけて
I put on some music
計画をねりねり
and hatch my plans.
今日はなんだかね
Today, somehow,
おもしろいこともないし
there's nothing really interesting,
リズムに揺られたいんだわ
and I just want to sway to the rhythm—
ワンルーム・ディスコ
a one room disco.
昼間みたいな街の明かりが
The city lights, bright as day,
星空を見えなくする
make the starry sky invisible.
たくさんのまぶしい光
So many dazzling lights
とけで消えちゃいそうだ
are about to melt away into nothing.
新しい場所で上手やっていけるかな
I wonder if I'll get by just fine in this new place,
部屋を片付けて
cleaning up my room
買い物に出かけよ
and heading out to shop.
遠い空の向こう
Beyond the distant sky,
新しい場所で上手やっていけるかな
I wonder if I'll get by just fine in this new place,
音楽をかけて計画をねりねり
playing music and hatching my plans.
今日はなんだかねおもしろいこともないし
Today, somehow, there's nothing interesting,
リズムに揺られたいんだわワンルーム・ディスコ
and I want to sway to the rhythm, a one room disco.
買い物に出かけよ
Let's go out shopping.
遠い空の向こうキミは何を思うの
Beyond the distant sky, what are you thinking?
たぶんできるはずって
Thinking that surely we can do it,
思わなきゃしょうがない
we have no choice but to believe.
新しい場所で上手やっていけるかな
I wonder if I'll get by just fine in this new place,
音楽をかけて計画をねりねり
playing music and hatching my plans.
今日はなんだかねおもしろいこともないし
Today, somehow, there's nothing interesting,
リズムに揺られたいんだわワンルーム・ディスコ
and I want to sway to the rhythm, a one room disco.
買い物に出かけよ
Let's go out shopping.
遠い空の向こうキミは何を思うの
Beyond the distant sky, what are you thinking?
たぶんできるはずって
Thinking that surely we can do it,
思わなきゃしょうがない
we have no choice but to believe.
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One room disco
ディスコ ディスコ
Disco, disco
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One room disco
ディスコ ディスコ
Disco, disco
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One room disco
ディスコ ディスコ
Disco, disco
都会の人ごみ 肩がぶつかってひとりぼっち
In the crowded city streets, bumping shoulders, all alone.
果てしない草原 風がビュンビュンとひとりぼっち
On endless grasslands, wind whistling by, all alone.
どっちだろう 泣きたくなる場所は
Which place is it where you want to cry?
2つマルをつけてちょっぴりオトナさ
Drawing two circles, acting just a bit more mature.
メチャメチャ苦しい壁だってふいに なぜか
Even when facing seemingly impossible walls, suddenly,
ぶつかる勇気と power 湧いてくるのは
why do courage and power to break through well up inside?
メチャメチャきびしい人たちがふいに見せた
When harsh people suddenly show
やさしさのせいだったりするんだろこうね
a touch of kindness, that must be why.
都市の人ごみ 肩がぶつかってひとりぼっち
In the crowded city, bumping shoulders, all alone
果てしない草原 風がビュンビュンとひとりぼっち
Endless grasslands, wind blowing, all alone
どっちだろう 泣きたくなる場所は
Which place makes you want to cry?
2つマルをつけて ちょっとりオトナさ
Marking two circles, just a little bit mature
メチャメチャ 苦しい壁だってふいに なぜか
Why is it that suddenly even the harsh walls...
ぶち壊す 勇気とpower 湧いてくるのは
break through, courage and power come welling up?
メチャメチャ きびしい人達がふいに 見せた
Why is it that suddenly harsh people showed...
やさしさのせいだったり するんだろうね
something that was actually kindness?
ア・リ・ガ・ト・ウ・ゴ・ザイ・マ・ス！
Thank you very much!
今まで 何回ヨロシク と元気に叫んだだろう
How many times have you shouted "Nice to meet you!" energetically until now?
今まで 何回サヨナラ と泣いて別れただろう
How many times have you cried saying "Goodbye" until now?
どっちだろう 比べて多い数は
Which place has more memories?
中にイコール書いて ちょっとりオトナさ
Writing an equal sign inside, just a little bit mature
メチャメチャ 悲しいときだってふいに なぜか
Why is it that even in extremely sad times...
乗り越える 勇気とpower 湧いてくるのは
courage and power to overcome come welling up?
ア・リ・ガ・ト・ウ・ゴ・ザイ・マ・ス！
Thank you very much!
今まで 何回ヨロシク と元気に叫んだだろう
How many times have you shouted "Nice to meet you!" energetically until now?
今まで 何回サヨナラ と泣いて別れただろう
How many times have you cried saying "Goodbye" until now?
どっちだろう 比べて多い数は
Which place has more memories?
中にイコール書いて ちょっとりオトナさ
Writing an equal sign inside, just a little bit mature
メチャメチャ 悲しいときだってふいに なぜか
Why is it that even in extremely sad times...
乗り越える 勇気とpower 湧いてくるのは
courage and power to overcome come welling up?
メチャメチャ やさしい人達がふいに 見せた
Why is it that suddenly kind people showed...
きびしさのせいだったり するんだろうね
something that was actually harshness?
ア・リ・ガ・ト・ウ・ゴ・ザイ・マ・ス！
Thank you very much!
都市の人ごみ 肩がぶつかってひとりぼっち
In the crowded city, bumping shoulders, all alone
果てしない草原 風がビュンビュンとひとりぼっち
Endless grasslands, wind blowing, all alone
どっちだろう 泣きたくなる場所は
Which place makes you want to cry?
2つマルをつけて ちょっとりオトナさ
Marking two circles, just a little bit mature
メチャメチャ 苦しい壁だってふいに なぜか
Why is it that suddenly even harsh walls...
ぶち壊す 勇気とpower 湧いてくるのは
break through, courage and power come welling up?
メチャメチャ きびしい人達がふいに 見せた
Why is it that suddenly harsh people showed...
やさしさのせいだったり するんだろうね
something that was actually kindness?
ア・リ・ガ・ト・ウ・ゴ・ザイ・マ・ス！
Thank you very much!
メチャメチャ 楽しいときだって忘れないよ
Even in extremely fun times, I won't forget,
いつでもま 勇気とpower なくさないよ
I will never lose courage and power forever.
メチャメチャ ひとりぼっちの人にあげる
Giving it to the lonely person,
唇の裏側に隠してある
hidden behind the lips...
ホ・ホ・エ・ミ・ノ・バ・ク・ダ・ン！
Smile bomb!
メチャメチャ 苦しい壁だってふいに なぜか
Why is it that suddenly even harsh walls...
ぶち壊す 勇気とpower 湧いてくるのは
break through, courage and power come welling up?
メチャメチャ きびしい人達がふいに 見せた
Why is it that suddenly harsh people showed...
やさしさのせいだったり するんだろうね
something that was actually kindness?
ア・リ・ガ・ト・ウ・ゴ・ザイ・マ・ス！
Thank you very much!
メチャメチャ 楽しいときだって忘れないよ
Even in extremely fun times, I won't forget,
いつでもま 勇気とpower なくさないよ
I will never lose courage and power forever.
メチャメチャ ひとりぼっちの人にあげる
Giving it to the lonely person,
唇の裏側に隠してある
hidden behind the lips...
ホ・ホ・エ・ミ・ノ・バ・ク・ダ・ン！
Smile bomb!
メチャメチャ 楽しいときだって忘れないよ
Even in extremely fun times, I won't forget,
いつでもま 勇気とpower なくさないよ
I will never lose courage and power forever.
メチャメチャ ひとりぼっちの人にあげる
Giving it to the lonely person,
唇の裏側に隠してある
hidden behind the lips...
ホ・ホ・エ・ミ・ノ・バ・ク・ダ・ン！
Smile bomb!
メチャメチャ 楽しいときだって忘れないよ
Even in extremely fun times, I won't forget,
いつでもま 勇気とpower なくさないよ
I will never lose courage and power forever.
メチャメチャ ひとりぼっちの人にあげる
Giving it to the lonely person,
唇の裏側に隠してある
hidden behind the lips...
ホ・ホ・エ・ミ・ノ・バ・ク・ダ・ン！
Smile bomb!
And that was Hohoemi no Bakudan!
Why is it not turning up?
You guys didn't hear anything, right?
も聞いてないよね？
You didn't hear anything, right?
You guys were deaf for a second, I'm sure, right?
何も聞いてない！ 大丈夫！
You didn't hear anything! It's fine!
Do you guys know what this is?
It's my boombox, ラジカセでございます！
It's my boombox, a ghetto blaster!
I will be using this later, so let me put it back down.
But I just wanted to do that.
That's my boombox! It changes the world, but I don't have Boin Goose.
Anyways, um... it's cool and retro, and actually...
I have a couple of announcements for the show, but first...
I want to talk to you about one obvious announcement: THE MERCH! Yes!
実は今回のライブはビッグなお知らせが本当にたくさんあるんですけど、その前にね、
Actually, there are so many big announcements for this live, but before that,
IRySの記念グッズ紹介しようと思います！
I'd like to introduce IRyS's anniversary merch!
Is it cute? I wanted to create a set that matches the retro feel of this live,
so let's take a look at what kind of goods are available!
ではどんなグッズがあるのか見ていきましょう！
Let's take a look at what kind of goods there are!
First off, we have The Concert PosteRYS (Poster).
Isn't it sexy? I wanted to make it look like a poster for an in-real-life concert.
This time, actually, um, continuing from last time, the illustration is by Pisto-sensei—
This time, actually, um, continuing from last time, the illustration is by Pisto-sensei...
次、I love Pirosuke-sensei's art.
Next, I love Pirosuke-sensei's art.
She has an amazing fashion sense.
The outfits are always so peak.
Yes, look at the sexy disco-style outfit.
Yes, it's sexy, right?
Yeah, it's sexy.
And next, we have the concert T-shirt-Rys.
It's my first time releasing a T-shirt,
if we don't count the Omocat ones.
You need to have a T-shirt for a live concert, of course, right?
I know we're not in an in-person venue,
And we still have more!
The third item is the backpack-Rys.
Yeah, it's like a bigger version of the...
the shoulder bag-Rys, which I think a lot of you guys liked.
And it's perfect for carrying all of your IRyS merch!
And finally, we have...
the YabaiRys keychain!
I know you guys and...
and me personally have all been wanting a doll that has this face.
Look at it.
She's so cute.
I wonder what she's thinking about.
Surely, say some thoughts.
When you press her, she makes a sound.
Surely, a saso sound.
You can put her on your backpack-Rys and take her everywhere with you!
The full set will include the backstage pass style card.
I'll be hand-signing the limited edition sets,
and the regular sets will be foil stamped as per usual.
And that's not all.
Every set will include a special...
Oh shit!
Holomen card for the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME.
You can only get this promo card if you buy the full set.
And surely it's IRyS card.
It must have like absolutely amazing stats.
Yeah, surely, surely.
If you haven't played yet, you can check out the card details and how to play on the official card game homepage,
so be sure to check it out!
Since it's IRyS card, it's definitely going to be super strong, I think.
And that's all for the merch announcements.
Merch sales will open after the main part of the live.
I still have another big announcement coming up,
so please stay until the end.
I can't wait to share it with you, man.
Yeah, we're already halfway...
Oh! Oh! Another one is starting!
Oh wait, I got to go! I got to go!
life goes on 満足してた
Life goes on, I was satisfied
少しの希望だけで
with just a little bit of hope.
待ってれば 誰かが未来決めてくれていた
Waiting around for someone to decide my future.
just got to get you back and bring it back on
なんて小さい自分なんだろう
What kind of small self was that?
bust it up!
here we go, 1, 2
move it up and break it!
今すぐ夢まで走ろう
Let's run straight to our dreams right now!
bring it back, hey, rock'n roll!!!
Bring it back, hey, rock 'n' roll!
Gamble, you gotta dive into a scramble!
ギリギリのステージ
On this razor-edge stage!
守るべきモノなんて実しはそんなにない
There's really not that much I need to protect.
give it up yo! give it up yo!
少しだけ強がって賭けましょう全部 play the game!
Act a bit tough, let's bet it all and play the game!
let's gamble, hey jumbo, now shake your bum and do the rumble
鋭くラインを三本
Three sharp lines drawn,
テンション上がりきりでボンボー
Energy peaked, bouncing away!
登場move三人衆 皆様の安眠中
The move trio appears during everyone's slumber.
爆音で『お前ウザい!』とか言われて延々と
With blast beats, endlessly told "You're annoying!"
i like to move it move it i'll make you move into it
国産のエグいノイズかます ギニギラギニギラ欲望さらす
Firing sick domestic noise, exposing glaring desires.
スタートからゴールまでまとめてワープして マッハ55で抜け出していこう
Warping straight from start to goal at Mach 55!
to your next stage
自分らしさ削って過ごしていた 代償に手に入れたのは古くさいモラル
The price for spending days chipping away at myself
just got to get you back and bring it back on
脆弱なこの群れから今 bust it up! here we go, back to
Now bust it up from this fragile flock! Here we go back to...
move it up and break it!
何も持たずに飛び出そう bring back yo it's the right time
Let's leap out with nothing at all, bring back yo it's the right time
hey boy, rock'n roll
Hey boy, rock 'n' roll!
Gamble, you gatta chance to make a rumble!
Gamble, you gotta chance to make a rumble!
研ぎ澄まされていく oh yeah!
Sharpening up, oh yeah!
Gamble, you gatta dive in to a scramble!
Gamble, you gotta dive into a scramble!
直感を信じて check it out come on!
Trusting your intuition, check it out, come on!
本命の君の愛 以外は欲しくなくて
Wanting nothing else but your true love.
give it up yo! give it up yo!
少しでも迷うもの 捨てましょう it's gonna feel so fine!
Discard any hesitation, it's gonna feel so fine!
break down
come on, hey, do the rumble
152! ムラムラとbeatが挑戦する モツMC 超ティーンエイジアー 人類最速rap芸者
152 beats challenging! Motsu MC, super teenager, the world's fastest rap geisha!
speakeasyへようこそ 大盤振舞う髑髏元 全部張ってすっちょうか? は! gamble rumble
Welcome to the speakeasy! Betting it all, ha! Gamble Rumble!
Gamble, you gatta chance to make a rumble!
Gamble, you gotta chance to make a rumble!
溢れ出る目眩が
Overflowing dizziness...
Gamble, you gatta dive in to a scramble!
Gamble, you gotta dive into a scramble!
ハジケそうな last game
This last game about to pop!
152! ムラムラとbeatが挑戦する
152 beats challenging...
モツMC 超ティーンエイジアー 人類最速rap芸者 speakeasyへようこそ 大盤振舞う髑髏元 全部張ってすっちょうか? は! gamble rumble
Motsu MC, super teenager, world's fastest rap geisha, welcome to the speakeasy!
Gamble, you gatta chance to make a rumble!
Gamble, you gotta chance to make a rumble!
溢れ出る目眩が
Overflowing dizziness...
Gamble, you gatta dive in to a scramble!
Gamble, you gotta dive into a scramble!
ハジケそうな last game
This last game about to pop!
Gamble, you gatta chance to make a rumble!
Gamble, you gotta chance to make a rumble!
ギリギリのステージ oh yeah!
On this razor-edge stage, oh yeah!
Gamble, you gatta dive in to a scramble!
Gamble, you gotta dive into a scramble!
一ミリも迷わず check it out come on!
Without a millimeter of doubt, check it out, come on!
一瞬の選択で すべてを失っても
Even if a split-second choice loses everything,
give it up yo! give it up yo!
後悔は見せないで 明るく負けて泣きましましょう
Show no regrets, let's brightly lose and cry!
bring back, hey, one more time!
bring back yo it's the right time
hey boy, rock'n roll
Hey boy, rock 'n' roll!
確実にあたしの 未来を巻き込んで
Involving my certain future,
恋は走り出した 君の手をつかんだ
love started running and I grabbed your hand.
両側から燃える 花火みたいだった
It was like fireworks burning from both sides.
視線もはがせない
I can't even tear my gaze away.
Oh, Step in Step in, Baby
どうして出逢えたの どうしてわたしなの
Why did we meet? Why is it me?
Boy, I fall in love with you
この瞬間も
Even at this moment.
タイトなジーンズにねじ込む わたしという戦うボディ
A fighting body squeezed into tight jeans,
どんな小さな願いにも 貫くチャンスをあげて
giving a chance to pierce through any tiny wish.
My Dream
破れたジーンズと 繊細すぎる目を 守ってあげたくて
Wanting to protect torn jeans and overly delicate eyes.
家族には言えない 大事なものくらい 自分で守れるよ
I can protect precious things myself that I can't tell family.
そこを飛び越えてよ
Jump right over that.
Oh, Step in Step in, Baby
無意味な強がりも 勝手なおしゃべりも
Meaningless bravado and selfish chatter,
Just, I fall in love with you
全部受け取って
Accept it all.
きみとわたし間に 愛が見つけられないなら 世界中のね どこにもそんなものないのよ My Dream
If love can't be found between you and me, it's nowhere in the world, my dream.
家族には言えない
Things I can't tell my family,
大事なものくらい 自分で作れるよ
things I hold dear—I can make them myself.
そこを飛び越えてよ
Leap right over that!
Oh, Step in, Step in Baby
無意味なつながりも 勝手な唇も
Even meaningless connections, even selfish lips—
Just, I fall in love with you
全部受け取って
Take it all in!
君とたちの間に 愛が見つけられないなら
If we can't find love between you and me,
世界中のどこにも そんなものないのね My Dream
Then there's no such thing anywhere in the world, My Dream.
Baby, I fall in love with you, we can make it last forever
Tell me what you want, come closer to me
Give me all your love, baby, I fall in love with you
We can make it last forever, tell me what you want, come to me
Give me all your love
離れちゃ意味ないじゃん 凛然としてたいじゃん
There's no point in separating, I want to stay dignified,
Boy, I fall in love with you, yeah, yeah
ここで戦って 走る鼓動を選んだ
Fighting right here, I chose this racing heartbeat.
ふたりという生きてるボディ
A living body of the two of us—
どんな確かな予感にも 信じる力をあげて My Dream
Give the power of belief to any certain premonition, My Dream!
タイトなジーンズにねじ込む 私という名の戦い
Cramming my identity into tight jeans—a battle called "me"!
どんな小さな願いにも 輝くチャンスをあげて My Dream
Give a chance to shine to even the smallest wish, My Dream!
Woo... Yeah...
Wow... yeah, yeah...
Fun Fun We hit the step step
同じ風の中 We know We love
in the same wind, we know, we love.
Oh Heat Heat (The) beat's like a skip skip
ときめきを運ぶよ Choo Choo TRAIN
carrying our excitement—Choo Choo TRAIN!
まだ知らない Zone
To a zone we don't know yet,
めざすよ Tonight
aiming for tonight.
リアルな時が止まる Edge of Time
Real time stands still at the edge of time.
誰も Cry or Smile
Everyone cries or smiles,
昨日の I forget
forgetting yesterday.
脱ぎ捨てて 自由になる good trip
Shedding it all to be free on a good trip.
月明かりに freak 誘えば my bro.
Enticing a freak in the moonlight, my bro.
みんな巻き込み 急ぐ edge of time
Pulling everyone in, rushing to the edge of time.
胸に Who's that guy 届く I don't care merry sympathy
"Who's that guy?" reaching our hearts—I don't care, melody, sympathy!
ひとつになる just now
Becoming one, just now
Fun Fun We hit the step step
同じ風の中 We know We love
In the same wind, We know We love
Oh Heat Heat (The) beat's like a skip skip
ときめきを運ぶよ Choo Choo Train
Carrying excitement, Choo Choo Train
まだ知らない Zone めざすよ tonight
Aiming for an unknown zone tonight,
リアルな時間が止まる edge of time
Real time stops at the edge of time.
誰も cry or smile 昨日 I forget
Anyone can cry or smile, I forget yesterday,
脱ぎ捨てて 自由になる good trip
Throwing it all off, a free good trip.
ビルの up side down
Upside down of buildings,
森を round and round
Round and round the woods,
抜け出して 始まるのさ good trip
Breaking out, the good trip begins.
胸に Who's that guy 届く I don't care
In my heart, Who's that guy reaches, I don't care,
merry sympathy 始まるの sanga train
Merry sympathy, the sanga train begins.
Fun Fun We hit the step step
So don't keep yourself to yourself We know We love
Oh Heat Heat (The) beat's like a skip skip
駆け出してから 飛び乗る chuu chuu train
Running out and jumping on, Choo Choo Train
Fun Fun We hit the step step
変わりそうな scene 追いかけ one night
Chasing a changing scene for one night,
出かけようこのドアに Say good-bye
Let's head out this door, Say good-bye.
Oh Heat Heat (The) beat's like a skip skip
ときめきを 運ぶよ chuu chuu train
Carrying excitement, Choo Choo Train
Fun Fun We hit the step step
肩を抱き合えば We know We love
Holding each other's shoulders, We know We love
Oh Heat Heat (The) beat's like a skip skip
駆け出して 飛び乗る chuu chuu train
Running out and jumping on, Choo Choo Train
La la la la...
Thanks everyone and that was Choo Choo Train with my lovely guest!
But we still have one more song to go. 残りあと1曲になってしまいました…
But we still have one more song to go. It's already down to our last song...
But you guys want an encore, don't you? Of course you do! まだまだライブ観たいよね? Of course you do!
But you guys want an encore, don't you? Of course you do! You still want to watch the live, right? Of course you do!
After this, I have a members-only encore live, so I would love it if you'd be able to join that for that as well.
After this, I have a members-only encore live, so I would love it if you'd be able to join that as well.
これからもね メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブもやります! ぜひメンバーシップ入ってね! So please join the fan club if you want to watch that! It's gonna be amazing.
We'll also be doing members-only encore lives! So please join the membership! So please join the family if you want to watch that! It's gonna be amazing.
It's and it's going to have some nice songs, yes! 歌も歌いますんでね、ぜひ楽しみにしててください。
And it's going to have some nice songs, yes! We'll be singing, so please look forward to it.
Before we move on to the next song though, I have an extra extra special announcement! みんなにスペシャルなお知らせがあります!
Before we move on to the next song though, I have an extra extra special announcement! I have a special announcement for everyone!
I have releasing a new EP! やっと新しいEPがリリースされます! すごい久しぶりの、その2年ぐらい? I think it's been like two years since my last one.
I'm releasing a new EP! A brand new EP is being released! It's been quite a while, about two years? I think it's been like two years since my last one.
Oh! It's so nice! And she called it YaBAI, タイトルがYaBAIになってます! It features car-vated love and four new songs!
Oh! It's so nice! And she called it YaBAI, the title is YaBAI! It features car-vated love and four new songs!
The concept is eurobeat, if you haven't noticed yet, and dance. Yeah, it's very euro-y in general though. And the digital release will be on July 12th midnight JST, which will be the 11th in the States. Yes!
えっどコンセプトがユーロ系になっています。もうとってもね車に合うようなEPになっています。ええとデジタルリリースが7月12日の、ええと0時で
Um, the concept is Eurobeat. It's an EP that fits driving really well. Um, the digital release is July 12th at, um, midnight...
But this EP will also have a physical release, and pre-orders will begin right after this stream!
あの、でもね、デジタルはそうなんですけど、フィジカルもなんと出します！
Um, but you know, while it's digital, we're also releasing a physical version!
フィジカルの販売は、この配信の後に...予約開始かがこの配信の後になります。
Physical sales will... pre-orders will start right after this stream.
There will be two versions of the physical release, each with a different jacket, each very beautiful,
and a set of two stickers you can use to decorate your smartphone or your card.
Yes, you can put it on your card 'cause one of them is going to be waterproof.
あのね、なんと今回のリリースは、2種類のジャケットの種類になっていると思います。
You know, this release will have two different jacket types.
両方ともすごい可愛いんでね。で、あとステッカーも2種類ずつ出ます。
Both are super cute! And we also have two kinds of stickers for each.
なので全部で4個...4個だけど、1種類買ったら2個、もう1種類買ったら2個っていう感じになってます。
So, about 4 in total... 4 items, but if you buy one kind you get 2, and another 2 for the other.
ぜひぜひ、スマホや車に貼っていただけると嬉しいな。その2枚のなかに1個は、もう防水になっているんで車にも貼ってください！
I'd be so happy if you stick them on your phone or car! One of the two sets is waterproof, so please put it on your car too!
And I will also be hand-signing a limited amount of copies and shipping them out randomly.
Yes, randomly. I'll be signing quite a decent amount though, so you will have a decent chance at getting one. Yay!
Gacha, everyone's favorite, my favorite gacha. Yes.
直筆サインも、あの限定の数...数？限定の数？直筆サインも、あの、やりますんですけど、
For the hand-signed copies, in a limited quantity... wait, limited quantity? I'll be doing hand-signed ones too, but
なんとそのランダム配付になっています。なので、買ったら直筆サインが当たってるかどうか楽しみだね！
they're distributed randomly. So when you buy one, it'll be exciting to see if you get a signed one!
もし、その直筆サインが当たる可能性を上げ たかったら、ね？何枚か買ってくれると嬉しいな。
If you want to increase your chances of winning a signed one, you know, I'd be happy if you bought a few copies.
あの、でもね、あの結構な数をサインしたんでね。まあそこそこのいい確率で当たるかとおもいます。
Well, I signed quite a lot, so I think you have a pretty decent chance of winning.
Anyways, I'm really excited to show you the new songs I've been working on.
Do you want to listen to one of them? Do you really want to listen to one of them?
Are you begging right now? You have to be begging and you need it right now just like free encore, encore stuff, you know? The usual.
しゃあないなぁ！
Oh well, you leave me no choice!
The last song will be a new song from the EP with a very, very special guest.
なんと最後の曲はこのEPに収録されている新曲を特別ゲストと一緒に歌います！もうとってもホットな新曲になっています。
And for the last song, we'll be singing a brand new song from this EP together with a special guest! It's a super hot new track.
It's gonna be a really hot, nice, euro song if you haven't, you know, realized that yet.
And I can't wait for you guys to play it in the car, I mean in the car, please play it there, okay?
And now, please listen to my new original, DIAMOND GIRLFRIEND!
No one can dull my shine tonight / No one can dull my shine
Save me, I think I'm freezing up, so cold inside
舞台はquiet room ふたり
The stage is a quiet room for two
Save me, I need a guiding touch in these dark times
恋人たちのシーン
A scene of lovers
Inside the maze of your heart, I'm the soul that strays
But baby look at me, you're not blind
Oh, can't you see that I can be refined
Your heart is super hot right now, it's time / To be your diamond girlfriend
Overheating love machine, burning hot!
Hot! Hot! Hot! (Untouchable)
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way
Overheating love machine, burning hot!
Hot! Hot! Hot! (On the rock machine)
Nothing stops this awakened soul / break it all, break it all, break it all
The Diamond Girlfriend, しとやかなキャラ豹変
The Diamond Girlfriend, my elegant persona transforms
ビートまとい まき散らすのはプリンプリンのSparkleだ
Wrapped in beats, scattering a bouncy sparkle
Just heat it and wheel it, make the sword バッチリ
Just heat it and wheel it, make the sword just right
まぶしさで目が眩むgem
A gem whose brightness dazzles your eyes
まぶしさで目が眩む Gem
A dazzling, blinding gem
Trust me, your weary eyes betray what you've tried to hide
言葉無しで伝わり
Conveyed without words...
Trust me, I'll never shy away from your dark side
空気が変わるフェイズ
A phase where the atmosphere changes
Under the pressure and fire, see these ashes reborn
Your rebirth
Let me show you who I really am, Oh yeah...
In the name of love, I'll be a gem Ah
In the name of love, I'll be a gem...
Your heart is super hot right now, it's time, I'll be your DIAMOND GIRLFRIEND
Your heart is super hot right now, it's time to be your Diamond Girlfriend
Overheating love machine, burning hot! hot! hot! hot! Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way
So precious girlfriend go go go
Overheating love machine, burning hot! hot! hot! hot! On the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul break it all break it all break it all break it all
No one can dull my shine tonight No one can dull my shine tonight
Now "C" is your atomic symbol
ぐるぐる回せ真っ赤赤になるまで Wimble
Spin around until it turns bright red, wimble
愛が足りないとか闇が深いほど
The less love there is, the deeper the darkness
価値ふえるGemあつかう I'm a jeweler さあ 踊リナサイ
Handling gems of increasing value, I'm a jeweler, come on and dance!
Shine on, shine bright, light my flame
Until it all melts away...
Are you ready?
Overheating love machine, burning hot! hot! hot! hot! Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way
So precious girlfriend go go go
Overheating love machine, burning hot! hot! hot! hot! On the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul break it all break it all break it all break it all
No one can dull my shine tonight No one can dull my shine tonight
Thank you so much for watching my live!
The CD for my new EP YaBaI will be open for pre-orders after this, and includes a new song Diamond Girlfriend that I just performed featuring Motsu-san.
The CD for my new EP "YaBaI" will be open for pre-orders after this, and includes the new song "Diamond Girlfriend" that I just performed featuring Motsu-san.
There are two versions that will be available for purchase: the YaBa Kawaii version and the YaBa Chic version.
The YaBa Kawaii jacket illustration is drawn by Maegju-san, and the YaBa Chic jacket illustration is drawn by Syagamu-san.
The jackets are reversible so you will be able to switch between the two no matter which version you buy. Both jackets are absolutely adorable!
The main difference between the two versions are the sticker set designs that will be included. Both sets are drawn by Lien-sensei.
There are two different types of stickers included with each EP version. One of which is a larger size and waterproof, so it would be great if you could put it on your car. The other is a smartphone size so you can take it with you wherever you go.
There are two different types of stickers included with each EP version. One of which is larger and waterproof, great for putting on your car, and the other is smartphone-sized to take with you anywhere.
Also, the alternate jacket may have a handwritten signature on it, so please look forward to it!
This EP is packed with your a-songs. I'm really looking forward to sharing them all with you and I hope you buy a copy!
This EP is packed with awesome songs. I'm really looking forward to sharing them all with you and I hope you buy a copy!
Stay tuned after the credits for the Diamond Girlfriend MV premiere, and I'll see you guys in the members-only part. Woo!
Thank you so much for watching
& celebrating my Birthday with me!
I put all my heart into this live &
I hope that you can continue
to support me in my singing journey
as we reach for the stars TOGETHER!
I love you guys!
いつもありがとう☆
Thank you always☆